[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 22]
[This story is purely fictional]
[Equality for Everyone, Justice in Administration]
Laogou.
You asked me to bring you here.
Did you recall something?
You fired a gun here.
Laogou.
It's a complicated story.
Did you
fire a gun here or not?
Take your gun out.
And shoot once more.
What?
Afraid that my memories will come back?
Open fire.
Again.
Zhang Qishan!
Again!
Again. Again!
Colonel Hatoyama.
How much longer do we need?
Qingwuzi said
the gate was here.
We need to operate the mechanism six times
to open it.
Operate it six times.
How many times has it been now?
The sixth, sir.
The mechanism.
The mechanism is unlocked.
Qingwuzi is right.
Let's go.
Yes.
Spare him.
- No. - Master.
No!
Laogou.
Master!
No.
What is going on?
Did you recall something?
Yes.
I feel
brokenhearted.
I am upset.
I also saw the Japanese.
But I couldn't recall
what exactly happened.
Can you let me try it?
Laogou.
What are you doing?
Freeze.
Put down the gun.
What in the world?
Did you
kill my man here?
I knelt and begged you,
but you didn't spare him.
Yes.
Why?
Because he violated the law.
Laogou.
It's
not what you think it is.
Put down the gun.
Master Zhang
can explain everything.
Don't just stand there.
Talk to your master now.
Master.
It's not what you think it is.
Don't...
Shut up!
I can't even remember myself.
I can't tell
if you're lying to me or not.
You can lie to one
or two people.
But you can't lie to everyone in the city.
I want to find out
what kind of person
stays by my side every day.
I want them to tell me
if you have hurt the people,
if you have betrayed your friends,
or if you
have any secret dealings.
No, Fifth Master.
Master Zhang isn't someone like that.
He's a righteous officer.
Yes, Fifth Master.
You are kind to us,
but Master Zhang
is also our benefactor.
That's right.
- After Master Zhang came to Changsha, - I agree.
our lives took a turn
for the better.
Right, everyone?
- Yes. - Yes.
I can tell you
what happened back then.
No need.
I just wanted to make sure
that you didn't kill the innocent.
The Japanese
brought me to this place.
It's a stage.
There were three people in opera costumes.
The child in the middle
was kneeling at the center.
Great, Fifth Master.
You recalled something.
What you drew
is Madam Wang's Lecture.
What is Madam Wang's Lecture?
It's...
Continue.
Someone opened fire.
But I'm not sure who they were shooting at.
And someone was talking.
He kept saying
Seioutsu, Rokkai.
Seioutsu, Rokkai?
Seioutsu...
Rokkai...
What does it mean, Fifth Master?
I don't know.
But they
probably weren't speaking Chinese.
When he said Rokkai,
a gate opened.
Then he brought me
to a river.
No.
It was not a river.
It wasn't outside.
But I could hear the sound of water.
Underground river.
Fifth Master, you're right.
Hatoyama
took the underground river.
But
how did they get down?
Could it be
they descended
from the stage?
You said Rokkai.
Say it again.
Seioutsu, Rokkai.
Louder.
It's Qingwuzi, six times, in Japanese.
Qingwuzi?
I remember it now.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama mentioned in his report
that he found the Otherworld Tower
when he was studying
Qingwuzi.
Perhaps it's the stage layout?
But we did it correctly thrice.
Do we have to do it three more times?
Impossible.
You can only rearrange the stage
three times.
There's no other way.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama knows far more
than what we do.
He probably learned that by studying Qingwuzi.
If that's the case,
Qingwuzi might be the key
that leads us to the underground river.
Tiezui.
I'll put you in charge of this.
Find out everything.
Yes, Master Zhang.
We'll head to Xie Jiu
and tell him
what happened.
[Otherworld Tower Map]
What we know for sure
is that beneath the stage of Madam Wang's Lecture
is the entrance
of the underground river.
[Underground River]
And this underground river
is the passage
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama used to enter the Xumi Realm.
Let's lay down
the details of our plan.
Master Zhang,
I don't mean to offend you,
but before we make
a plan,
shouldn't we find out
what is inside the Xumi Realm?
That way, we know what we're getting into.
Go ahead.
If you remember,
Ding Qiansui
was imprisoned
deep inside
the secret cell under Master Zhang's residence.
How did
Hatoyama pierce through his chest
and kill him
with his hand?
Also,
that Japanese soldier who went to get water.
No matter how many times we killed him,
he always came back alive.
Moreover,
Master Zhang, you killed
a Zhainiangniang.
Judging from its serial number,
it's not the only one.
In the Xumi Realm,
there might
be more monsters like it.
Tiezui is right.
Be it
killing someone remotely
and bringing the dead back,
Hatoyama must have only mastered
all these tricks upon entering
the Xumi Realm.
Otherwise, he would have already killed you
when you were in the Otherworld Tower.
Yes.
That's what I mean.
The Xumi Realm
is dangerous.
And the Otherworld Tower
is just the appetizer
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama left us
to keep us intrigued.
If it's just an appetizer,
let's talk about the main dish.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
knows our literature
and mystic arts very well.
If his study continues,
he will become a threat.
We need to eliminate him as soon as possible.
But Master Zhang,
Hatoyama
leads a troop that he has trained
for years.
They are elite soldiers.
The Xumi Realm is dangerous.
If you want to mobilize your men,
you need to send in at least
a company
to fight them.
But Changsha is in a delicate
situation,
and Huo Wenhai is watching you closely.
If you mobilize your men now,
it might...
You're right.
A big number is a disadvantage,
and it might even draw attention.
We
must handle this matter swiftly.
Like how?
I'll take Xiaoyu
and you
with me
to capture Hatoyama.
Master Zhang,
I'll stay out of this.
You see,
you want to capture Hatoyama.
My presence
is a dead weight.
I shouldn't be there.
- I shouldn't be there. - Have I not
made myself clear just now?
Hatoyama is an expert in mystic arts.
Among everyone here,
only you have knowledge of it.
You must come with us.
Master Zhang,
- I should... - Sit down.
Master Zhang.
What about this?
We can communicate using pigeons.
I'll wait for you in Xiangxi.
If I come with you,
you have to capture the culprit
while protecting me.
I'll just
be an extra burden.
I should sit this one out.
I'll go with you.
Laogou.
Now is not the time to...
This monster here.
I think I've seen it.
You remember this monster?
I can't recall everything now.
But I'm sure
I've seen it.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama laid down an elaborate trap
in the Otherworld Tower
to capture you.
And
you have a very powerful talent.
You can tame animals.
You
tamed this monster.
I tamed
this monster?
Yes.
Am I that good?
No wonder.
No wonder you spent your family fortune
to get me back.
You really know what's good for you.
Laogou.
It was Xie Jiu
who spent his family fortune.
What are you on about?
It's fine.
It's for the Mystic Nine.
I'm doing this for Master Zhang.
Master Zhang,
if I have tamed this monster,
then I play an important role
in this matter.
All the more reason for me to come.
No.
Why?
I cannot fight
while ensuring your safety.
Ensuring my safety?
If you can protect Tiezui,
you can protect me as well.
Besides,
I can fight too.
I can protect myself.
No.
You lost your memories.
You will rest here and recover.
I am already implicated
in this matter.
You said yourself
that I had tamed this monster.
If the Japanese
use it to kill someone,
that makes me
a murderer.
Also,
I can see many images
in my head.
I can't recall everything now,
but if I go back there,
I might recall everything.
I have to be there.
He's right.
No.
You...
Laogou.
Master Zhang.
This is...
Just tell me
why you must join us.
Like you, I want
to protect everyone in this city.
If you can do it,
so can I.
All right.
You can come with us.
However,
you will stay by my side
during the whole journey.
Don't worry.
Tiezui and I
will be under your command.
Master Zhang,
let me join you.
No.
Why?
You'll hold the fort in Changsha.
Xie Jiu.
After we go down,
Huo Wenhai will surely do something.
Please
protect yourself.
Don't do anything reckless.
Don't worry, Master Zhang.
I always pick my battles.
Master Zhang.
Take care.
[Taihe Pleasure House]
Master Zhang, it's right inside.
Come.
Wow.
It's so deep.
Master Zhang,
this well is how Ding Qiansui
dropped supplies
to the Japanese.
We widened the passage
several days ago.
It now leads directly to the Otherworld Tower.
Laogou.
This is yours.
You know how to use it.
It's all mine?
The descent will be long
and fast.
Make sure you keep up with me.
Don't worry.
Let's go.
Careful.
Master Zhang.
You're so fast.
You were very agile too.
You merely forgot.
Really?
I really want to regain my memory soon.
We searched several times after we widened the passage,
but we found nothing.
So this is the Otherworld Tower?
This place collapsed once.
The situation is unclear.
Be vigilant.
Understood.
I'll follow you.
All right.
I can walk.
Master Zhang.
I've gone through the ancient records.
You need to rearrange the stage six times.
Arrange it
correctly three times.
Then incorrectly for another three times.
The entrance to the underground river
will then appear.
Why the hassle?
I'm not the Otherworld Patriarch.
How would I know?
Master Zhang.
This follows
the Li's Calculations of Five.
Three rights, three wrongs.
Mix rights in wrongs.
Mix wrongs in rights.
We did
three rights, two wrongs last time.
If we arrange it incorrectly one more time,
will Peng Qiao appear?
That's right.
Wait by the entrance.
I'll revisit the place with Fifth Master.
You told me last time about
Peng Ju and Peng Zhi.
It's Peng Qiao this time.
What
is it?
You'll find out soon.
I...
That's all you got, Peng Qiao?
Did you recall anything?
My friend,
you could've helped me kill it.
Must I do it myself?
Next time,
don't force me
if I can't recall anything.
Otherwise, I'll die in your hands
before we reach the Xumi Realm.
Master.
I found another contraption.
It's well hidden.
No wonder I didn't notice it before.
Help me get up at least.
Let's go.
I came
to ask you for a favor.
I hope you can ask
your men
to bring me to the Xumi Realm.
When Fifth Master of the Mystic Nine
escaped from the underground river in Xiangxi,
the people from Xinyue Restaurant
fished him out.
Just tell me
the exit of the underground river.
I can follow upstream
and find a way in.
That's a death wish,
miss.
Just give up on it.
My men
have investigated that river.
It's very dangerous.
Not only does it have a complicated system
of undercurrents,
but it also houses
a giant beast.
If you...
The danger will not dissuade me.
Why are you so stubborn?
Must you
go there?
Truth be told,
when I went to the Otherworld Tower
with Master Zhang,
it was to settle my clan's debts.
That was why I worked
as Ding Qiansui's informant
and did his bidding.
At first, I thought it was just a simple job.
But many things
have happened down there.
Master Zhang and the rest
went through a lot.
So did I.
This time, they went to the Xumi Realm
to end things for good.
I can't just stand around and do nothing.
Besides,
I also have some knowledge
that might be important to them.
So you don't think that Zhang Qishan
can settle the whole thing.
I do.
But it doesn't mean
my responsibility ends here.
There are things I must do.
Please have faith in me.
I do not
fight a losing battle.
You're just like my daughter.
So opinionated.
She never listens to me.
We all
want to walk
our own path.
Fine.
If that is your final decision,
and you don't regret it,
I'll ask Gun Yi to go with you.
He has a good memory
and can fight very well.
Thank you.
Thank you, Godfather.
[Changsha Garrison Command]
Officer Huo.
You need me?
Zhang Wenshu.
I received an urgent telegram from the Ministry of War.
It says there have been
cultist activities in Changsha
and the city's safety is compromised.
Defense Commander Zhang Qishan
has abandoned his post.
Garrison Captain Xu Renqing is thereby appointed
as the interim Defense Commander
in charge of this case.
It's an order from the Ministry of War.
Cultist activities?
Sir,
this is a serious matter.
We have never heard about it before.
And now, we are changing the defense commander?
Besides, we did not receive
the notice either.
Right. This is a big problem
but where is your commander?
Should we wait
until the cultists
burn our city
before we beg you
to appoint a new defense commander?
You guys
have worked a lot lately.
You've done well.
And I see that.
So I found an opportunity
to give you and your men
some respite.
Please
hand over the task.
Allow me
to verify the order.
Do you not trust me?
Verify it.
Take it with you.
Take your time.
Zhang Qishan's office
needs to be vacated.
Bring some men with you.
Be cordial.
We wouldn't want to tire the Zhang Clan's soldiers.
Yes.
[Notice]
A new order from the garrison!
The Honghua cult has spread
[Xiangchun Gate]
into Changsha.
They are a dangerous cult.
From now on,
Changsha will be placed under curfew.
No one can go out unless you hold
a special pass.
Those who sneak out
will be punished according to the military rules.
Something bad has happened.
They are appointing a new defense commander.
Xu Renqing will take over.
It seems like Huo Wenhai
is stirring up trouble again when Master is away.
Listen carefully.
I need you
to do something.
[Xiangxi]
Miss Huo.
The chests came from upstream.
We fished them out here.
Thanks.
I'll take over from here.
Oh.
Master prepared some supplies
for you.
The underground river is convoluted.
Please exercise caution.
Thanks.
Careful.
We finally found the exit.
Master.
The grass has been stepped on
and pulled.
The Japanese
must have come out
to this place.
This is a key passage to the Xumi Realm.
By right,
it should be heavily guarded.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama is meticulous.
He knows Laogou has escaped,
so he must have predicted that I would come here.
However, there are no guards.
It might be a trap.
Stay vigilant, everyone.
Master Zhang,
perhaps
Fifth Master and I will return to the underground river
and wait for your updates?
- No. - No.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama knows
that we are in the mountains.
From now on,
do not leave the formation.
Xiaoyu, watch him closely.
Yes.
I'll follow you.
Eighth Master.
Master Zhang.
Do you think there are
Zhainiangniangs in this mountain?
Master.
Everything is burnt to a crisp.
Given the number of items here,
there should've been some residue.
They probably stationed some men here to make sure
that nothing was left behind.
This is how a special agent
usually leaves a scene.
If this is just to set up
an ambush,
it'll be an overly
costly ambush.
They burned all their watches.
For some reason.
Perhaps time doesn't matter
where they go.
It'll only be a burden.
This cave
sounds like a clock.
It's the sound made by the wind
between the rocks.
Fingers are numb.
Do you recall anything?
But I drew this picture.
They burned everything.
But why did they
keep the papers?
There are claw marks.
Something dangerous
might have happened here.
I used to stay here.
Master.
It's a dead end.
I was
afraid of this place.
What was in here?
Probably what
I killed.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
imprisoned you here
to tame the Zhainiangniang.
When we were in Xiangxi,
we found out
that the Japanese had mastered
how to tame a Zhainiangniang.
Give me some time.
I'll recall everything.
Just give me some time.
I'll recall
everything that happened here.
Laogou.
Give me some time.
In an operation, do not
get carried away by your emotion.
Do not obsess over it.
Otherwise, you'll be trapped in it.
Our priority now
is to locate Hatoyama.
Hatoyama has abandoned this camp.
They probably
are heading to the Xumi Realm.
We have
to find a way in quickly.
I will recall everything.
Come.
Master.
We have been following
the Japanese's trail.
Is there going to be a trap?
There are only four of us.
We would have already died if there was a trap.
They could've attacked us anytime.
Just proceed.
No flies in here.
How weird.
Wow.
What is this tall wall?
It's the wall of the Otherworld Tower.
Xingxiu seal.
It's the same.
Master Zhang.
Is this a new Otherworld Tower?
Or...
Or could it be that
we're back in Changsha?
This is not Changsha.
It's a new place.
How are you so sure?
Because our ropes are not here.
Right.
Master Zhang.
You're entering it just like that?
It's the Japanese's territory.
Master Zhang!
Laogou's mark.
A passage underwater.
Laogou's secret code.
It probably means it's the entrance.
It seems like I can get there from underwater.
[Xumi Realm]
Xumi Realm.
This is the Xumi Realm?
Perhaps
the Xumi Realm
is another Otherworld Tower?
But it doesn't make sense.
Why is it so new?
By right,
the Otherworld Patriarch
built the Otherworld Tower back then
to enter
the Xumi Realm.
Therefore,
the Xumi Realm
should be older than the Otherworld Tower.
But it looks
so fresh, like it's newly built.
Fresh paint on an old stele?
Something's afoot.
Master.
The walls around us are solid.
No secret passage
or contraption.
Where did the Japanese go then?
Master Zhang.
Look.
The murals are different.
Master Zhang,
it probably is the various spells
from various sects.
You have
Soultrap Spell,
Illusion Dispelling Chant,
[Illusion Dispelling Chant]
Mind Manipulation,
[Teleportation]
and Teleportation.
So
the Xumi Realm
is a repository of spells.
Then,
in that case,
Hatoyama came here
to learn spells.
When he mastered them,
he returned to Japan with the spells.
Let's finish reading first.
Master Zhang.
I think I know
why it's a dead end here.
It says there's a spell
called Tower Cultivation.
[Tower Cultivation]
It means
while it's
a dead end,
it is not the end.
It needs to be grown.
Nourish the seed
with fire and water.
Then,
the tower shall rise,
and the door shall open.
Master Zhang.
In other words,
the dead end here means
that the seed hasn't sprouted yet.
Once the spell is activated,
the tower
will sprout.
Is it
waiting for us to plant a seed?
What seed?
I...
It doesn't say how.
But to grow something,
you plant a seed
and water it.
But the problem is...
Where do we plant it?
What is the seed?
This stele, perhaps?
Is it
the seed
of the Xumi Realm?
Laogou!
When we're this deep,
we have to be cautious.
How else are we supposed to grow it?
A calabash will sprout
within three days.
Is it going to take three years
to grow a tower?
It's a spell.
We can't measure it
with time.
Anyway, I highly doubt
that the stele is the seed.
So how do we grow it?
If it needs to sprout
and expand,
do you think
that perhaps the seed
is actually this entire area?
It doesn't work.
Let me try that spot.
Master,
are we really growing a tower here?
It doesn't hurt to let them try.
More importantly,
the Japanese were here.
But it's all sealed shut.
How did they get in?
It must be a trick.
Since this place shares the same layout
as the Otherworld Tower
in Changsha,
let's dig a passage here
like we did
last time.
Yes.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪